Welcome to America.
The Brutalist is a drama film directed by Brady Corbet.
When an innovative modern architect flees post-war Europe, he
is given the opportunity to rebuild his legacy.
Set during the dawn of the modern United States (in Pennsylvania), his wife joins him,
and their lives are forever changed by a demanding, wealthy patron.
László Tóth, played by Adrien Brody.
Erzsébet Tóth, played by Felicity Jones.
Harrison Lee Van Buren Sr, played by Guy Pearce.
Harry Lee, played by Joe Alwyn.
Zsófia, played by Raffey Cassidy.
Maggie Lee, played by Stacy Martin.
The Brutalist is a 2024 epic period drama film directed and produced by
Brady Corbet, who co-wrote the screenplay with Mona Fastvold.
It stars Adrien Brody as a Jewish-Hungarian architect and severely traumatized Holocaust survivor who
emigrates to the United States, where he struggles to recover and get his life back on track.
The cast also features Felicity Jones, Guy Pearce, Joe Alwyn, Raffey Cassidy,
Stacy Martin, Emma Laird, Isaach de Bankolé, and Alessandro Nivola.
The film was shot using the VistaVision format which had
been originally developed in the 1950s.
A co-production of the United States, the United Kingdom, and Hungary, The Brutalist premiered at the 81st Venice
International Film Festival on September 1, 2024, where Corbet was awarded the Silver Lion for Best Direction.
It was released in the United States by A24 on December 20, 2024; in Hungary by UIP-DunaFilm on January 23, 2025; and
in the United Kingdom by Focus Features through Universal Pictures International on January 24, 2025.
The film received critical acclaim and grossed $50.4
million against a $9.6 million budget.
Among multiple accolades, the film earned ten nominations at the 97th Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, winning for Best Cinematography, Best Original Score, and Best Actor for Brody.
At the 82nd Golden Globe Awards, it won three awards,
including Best Motion Picture – Drama.
It was named one of the top ten films of 2024 by the American Film Institute.
The film explores themes of new york city, immigrant, prostitute,
husband wife relationship, philadelphia, pennsylvania.
The tone is dark and emotional.